Michael Penhallegon

Seattle, WA 98106 / (425) 423-9426 / mike@hematite.tech

Summary:

Recent college graduate with a focus on computer science. Has a diverse skill-sets from technology driven, application development and data analytics, to mentorship and organizing. Has utilized mixtures of skillset to develop projects utilized to transition to a database to maintain contacts, analytically investigate health disparities and most recently, substantially streamline check-in for college orientation process.

- 7-years of personal and professional experience with Python and advanced knowledge of Java and SQL
- Strong experience organizing events and practicing in collaborative leadership
- Emerging health researcher, utilizing cross-disciplinary skills to analyze problems and implement solutions

Professional Experience:

Juno Therapeutics

Seattle, WA

Research Associate

August 2018-Present

Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center

Seattle, WA

Research Intern, HIV Vaccine Trial Network Core Lab

April 2018-June 2018

- Completed thorough literature review and prepared results for publication in an academic journal.
- Contributed to a qualitative research project investigating HIV/AIDS stigma among HIV+ and HIV- men
- Refactored and published an R library, to linearly interpolate Census-data to generate heath metric values.

Summer Research Intern

June 2017-August 2017

- Developed a project in analyzing connections, using R, Python and Tableau, between home value and health disparities in African-American neighborhoods using public census and health data.
- Contributed to a research project to analyze improving retention of minorities in medical trials.

The Evergreen State College

Olympia, WA

September 2017-June 2018

Quasr Tutor

- Tutored mathematics up to differential calculus, discrete mathematics, programming and digital logic
- Learned and used equity-minded pedagogy to tutor and engage students in using quantitative skill sets

Outreach and Retention Advisor, TRiO Student Success

June 2016-June 2018

- Advised and mentored first-generation/low-income students in navigating college and achieving success.
- Provided one-on-one scholarship and resume writing support.
- Served as a teaching assistant for classes; Organized workshops for internships and scholarships
- Assisted linking college administration to students through development of job descriptions, running VP candidate student forums and recruitment of students to college committees

New Student Orientation Leader

June 2017-September 2017

• Engaged, advised and mentored new undergraduate students during orientation week.

Penhallegon 1

• Lead and help organize orientation planning and logistics

Stonewall Youth, Olympia, WA

Olympia, WA

Programming Coordinator

October 2015-June 2016

- Developed programming for at-risk LGBTQ youth; Helped maintain drop-in hours for participants
- Developed backup plan; edited and maintained WordPress site including backup and software updates
- Utilized Python and R to clean and restore both participant and donor data. Normalized data from legacy systems.

Peninsula College

Port Angeles, WA

Office Assistant, Longhouse Diversity Services

February 2014-June 2014

- Coordinated event management for two large campus-wide events
- Maintained, updated and transitioned tribal contact database from Microsoft Excel to Access

Amazon.com Kennewick, WA

Customer Service Associate III-Kindle

June 2009-November 2011

- Provided replacement and warranty service while resolving software and hardware problems.
- Provided thorough technical support for customers utilizing multiple different computer platforms
- Met and regularly exceeded metrics of quality for call times and customer service
- Filed feedback and bug reports, utilizing JIRA, and kept customers informed of updates as needed.
- Developed internal team tools using HTML/CSS and Javascript to streamline customer service workflows

Education:

The Evergreen State College

September 2015-June 2018

Bachelor of Art, emphasis in Computer Science and Public Health Studies

Volunteer Experience:

Nomenus, Active Member, June 2009-December 2017

The Evergreen State College Provost Search Committee, Member, September 2016-Januarary 2017

President's Student Advisory Committee, December 2015-present

Black Focus 2016-present, Collective Member

Peninsula College Rainbow Alliance 2013-2015, Vice-President

Peninsula College Shades of Color Club 2013-present, Secretary (2013-2014) President (2014-2015)

Skills:

General: 65 wpm, interpersonal skills, customer service, and consensus decision-making. **Computing:** Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook), Tableau. Mac, Windows, and Linux desktop environments. **Programming and Software Development**: Python, R, Java, HTML, PostgreSQL, Mariadb, jQuery, git, Trac, test-driven development (TDD)

Professional Memberships:

Association for Computing Machinery 2014-present, Member

American Public Health Association, 2017-present, Student Member